Luciano Perez

Fullstack Developer Java

M lucianoperez12@gmail.com | ● Buenos Aires, Argentina

in LinkedIn | personal website | GitHub

My name is Luciano Perez, and I am a Fullstack Developer at Ensolvers, specializing in technologies such as Java with Spring Boot and React with TypeScript. I am currently in my third year of pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Systems at Universidad Nacional de Lanus. I am a dedicated professional committed to continuous learning and constant personal and professional growth, always focusing on improving my skills and deliver high-quality results in every project I contribute

ABOUT ME

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer Java

April 2024 - Current

Ensolvers

- Develop several new features for a project with over 3,000 users, prioritizing scalability and user experience. Received highly positive feedback from users, emphasizing its impact on improving their overall experience
- Led the migration and modularization of legacy code, transforming monolithic JavaScript scripts into maintainable and test-covered TypeScript modules, and optimizing database interactions and backend logic to enhance performance and maintainability.
- Specialize in backend development with Java and Spring Boot, and frontend development with React and TypeScript, delivering robust and scalable solutions.
- Analyze, design, develop, test, and implement key functionalities, ensuring quality through comprehensive testing, and actively monitoring performance in production using tools like AWS CloudWatch and New Relic, identifying bottlenecks, and optimizing efficiency.
- Ensure high code quality and coverage by writing extensive unit and integration tests with JUnit, Jest, and Mockito, maintaining high-quality standards across new features.
- Proactively identify and fix bugs across the application, delivering rapid hot-fixes directly to production to ensure minimal disruption to users and maintain high system reliability.

Functional Analyst May 2023 - April 2024

Mercado Libre (Vendor) | Voolkia Software & Services

- Developed new scraping and product matching strategies to enhance data analysis effectiveness.
- Conducted product validation and review across multiple platforms to ensure data accuracy.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to align efforts and optimize processes.
- Committed to continuous process improvement and optimization to boost efficiency.
- Created and managed comprehensive documentation for knowledge sharing and process clarity.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Typescript, Javascript, SQL, HTML/CSS

Technologies: React, Spring Boot, AWS (CloudWatch, S3, OpenSearch, EC2), MySQL, Kafka, Microservices,

Docker, Hibernate/JPA

Soft Skills: Proactivity, Teamwork, Communication, Adaptability, Problem-solving, Empathy, Time management

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Systems

Universidad Nacional de Lanus

March 2022 - Current

March 2012 - June 2021

First Certificate in English (Cambridge)

Knightsbridge School of English

Sports Events System

Built a Java-based sports event management system for matches, teams, stadiums, divisions, and cities.

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, MySQL, Angular, Typescript, Hibernate,

Portfolio Repository Deploy A website where you can find my projects, and information about my skills and experience.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript,

PROJECTS

Notes App Repository

Repository

Built a Notes Single Page Application, with different functionalities.

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate

LANGUAGES

Spanish Native

English Advanced